homelessworldcup.org 2019-12-09

# Privacy Notice - Homeless World Cup

### PRIVACY NOTICE

At Homeless World Cup Foundation, we’re committed to respecting your privacy and keeping your personal information safe.

Through this notice, we have provided detailed information on when and how we collect your personal data, how we use it and how we keep it secure.

We may collect personal information about you when you:

  * ask about our activities
  * register with us for information
  * sign up for publications or newsletters
  * volunteer or fundraise for us
  * participate in one of our events
  * make a donation to us
  * telephone, write, contact us online, or otherwise provide us with your personal information

This can include information such as your name, communication preferences, email address, postal address, IP address, telephone number, mobile number, date of birth or bank account details so we can process donations, or information as to whether you are a taxpayer to help us to claim gift aid.

We will not rent, sell or swap your personal information to other organisations for their own marketing activities.

### OUR WEBSITE

When someone visits www.homelessworldcup.org we use Google Analytics, to collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns. We do this so we can learn how our website is performing and which areas of the website are most popular. This information is processed anonymously. We do not make any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website.

### NEWSLETTER SIGN-UP

When you join our mailing list, you will receive campaigns about the work we do, our latest news and volunteering opportunities. We use a third-party provider, MailChimp, to deliver our newsletter. We gather statistics around email opening and clicks to help us monitor and improve our e-newsletter. Please refer to MailChimp’s privacy notice for more information. You can unsubscribe to our mailings at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any of our emails or by emailing us at info@homelessworldcup.org.

### EVENT PARTICIPANTS

We do not collect sensitive personal information about our volunteers and participants unless there is a clear reason for doing so, for example, relating to your health, and only where appropriate – such as participation in one of our events where we may ask you for dietary and ongoing medical requirements, or where we need to ensure that we provide appropriate support to enable you to participate in an event.

We will only collect sensitive personal data with the participants’ consent, and clear notices will be provided on applications for events and other relevant forms and communications, so you know what information we need and why we need it.

### SERVICE PROVIDERS

We use third-party service providers (such as fundraising agencies, direct mailing companies, and software platform providers) to help us deliver our events and communications.

We may give relevant persons within these service providers access to your personal information, but only to allow them to perform their services for us. Some service providers may be based outside of the European Economic Area (EEA) however, we will endeavour to ensure that any data transfers outside of the EEA are carried out in compliance with relevant data protection legislation and that the processing of your data is subject to appropriate security measures.

### LEGAL REQUIREMENTS

We may disclose your personal/sensitive personal information when required to by law, for example, to HMRC for tax purposes or to police forces for the prevention or detection of crime. Further, we safeguard the sharing of such information by using formalised information sharing agreements with organisations where appropriate, or on an ad hoc basis after ensuring the request and disclosure are legally compliant.

### ACCESS TO YOUR INFORMATION

Under GDPR you have the right to view, amend, or delete the personal information that we hold. If you wish to make any changes please email us on info@homelessworldcup.org.
